Adams-Morgan Community Council 011
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Adams-Morgan Community Council Records
1946-1967
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Adams-Morgan Community Council
011
0.25 Linear feet
1 Boxes
Arrangement
The collection was processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
The Adams-Morgan Community Council was formed in the late 1950s as a result of a two-year demonstration project to improve the neighborhood, which had deteriorated over the prior decade. The project sought to build viable organizations that could plan and work for improvements in blighted areas of Adams-Morgan. The Council was established towards the end of the project as a unified voice to represent various community and interest groups, including the Midway Civic Association, The Kalorama Citizens Association, the Adams-Morgan Better Neighborhood Conference, as well as various block associations formed during the project. The Council worked to improve health, welfare, education, and recreation for the Adams-Morgan community.
Custodial History
Unknown donor.
Related Materials
Records of the Adams-Morgan Better Neighborhood Conference (Collection 18)
Adams-Morgan: Democratic Action to Save a Neighborhood, a report prepared by the Office of Urban Renewal, District of Columbia, Stein and Marcou Associations, and American University (call number: 711.097 D623).
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, minutes, announcements, budgets, and clippings. Topics covered include housing, racial discrimination, and community organizations.
Housing; Neighborhoods; Associations, institutions, etc; Adams Morgan (Washington, D.C.); Community organization; Discrimination; Organizational Records; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc)
- Adams-Morgan News, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Adams-Morgan News, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Clippings, 1946-1964 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Discrimination Clippings, 1946-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Discrimination Clippings, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Organizations, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Hollyday House and other community organizations, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Housing, 1959-1961 (Box 1)
  - Housing issues, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Non-discrimination policy for the D.C. government, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Administrative Records, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Meeting minutes and financial records, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Summer Camp, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Summer Camp, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)